Xavier University student academic achievement assessment planning records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University student academic achievement assessment planning records
1993-2007
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Office of the Provost and Chief Academic Officer
1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
This is a collection of planning documents formulated in response to the North Central Association's Commission on Institutions of Higher Education. It includes reports submitted to North Central: the 1993 Xavier Outcomes Assessment Committee's Final Report and the 1995 report. It also includes annual departmental planning updates (with exceptions) for the years 1998-2007.
XUA-40
History of Xavier University student academic achievement planning
In response to the North Central Association's 1989 academic assessment mandate, Xavier's Academic Vice President formed an ad hoc Outcomes Assessment Committee in the Fall of 1991. The Committee's Final Report was issued and submitted to North Central in 1993. In 1995 North Central Association mandated that all institutions formulate and submit more detailed assessment plans. On June, 1995 Xavier submitted its Plan for the Assessment of Student Academic Achievement. Beginning in 1998 each academic department submitted to the Associate Vice President for Academic Affairs a yearly update indicating how it had implemented, and, where necessary, amended it's academic assessment plan.
Not specified
Scope and Content
This is a collection of planning documents concerning the assessment of student academic achievement at Xavier University. It includes the 1993 ad hoc Outcomes Assessment Committee and the 1995 Xavier University reports to the North Central Association. Annual updates submitted by departments within the three colleges of the university are also found.
Not specified
Statement of Arrangement
This collection is organized by series:
Correspondence
Reports: 1993 Final Report
Reports: 1995 Report, with Annual Departmental Updates by College
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Planning; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Evaluation; Academic achievement--Evaluation
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Outcomes Assessment Committee
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Correspondence, 1995-1998
  - Correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Reports: Outcomes Assessment Committee Final Report, 1993 June
  - Outcomes Assessment Committee Final Report, 1993 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Reports: 1995 Report and Annual Departmental Updates, by College, 1995-2007
  - 1995 Report: Introductory Materials, 1995 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1995 Report: College of Arts and Sciences (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - College of Arts and Sciences: Updates, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - College of Arts and Sciences: Updates, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - College of Arts and Sciences: Updates, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - College of Arts and Sciences: Updates, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - College of Arts and Sciences: Updates, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1995 Report: College of Social Sciences (Part I) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1995 Report: College of Social Sciences (Part 2) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - College of Social Sciences: Updates, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - College of Social Sciences: Updates, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - College of Social Sciences: Updates, 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - College of Social Sciences: Updates, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - College of Social Sciences: Updates, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - College of Social Sciences: Updates, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1995 Report: Williams College of Business (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Williams College of Business: Updates, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Williams College of Business: Updates, 2003-2007 (Box 3, Folder 20)